# VICKIANA MEDINA

Corona, NY 11368 | 646-515-0314 | VMedina927@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated and adaptable accounting and administrative professional with 12+ years of experience in versatile industries providing administrative support, data analysis and managing accounting processes. Established expertise in accounts payable/receivable. processes, administrative management and human resources processes. Highly organized in managing priorities, projects and tasks while maintaining a positive attitude and desire to excel in a remote working environment.

#### SKILLS & ATTRIBUTES

- Microsoft Office Suite
- Video Conferencing & Workplace Connectivity Tools
- ADP & QuickBooks
- Accounts
   Payable/Receivable
   Processes
- Process
  Improvement
- Interpersonal & Written
  Communication
- Data Analysis & Billing Processes
- Problem Solving & TimeManagement
- Bilingual: English & Spanish
- Organization & Project Management

August 2017 – December 2018

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Pro Design Inc., Astoria, NY

Associate Data Analyst

- Supported business operations through data mining to uncover insights, identify market trends and inflection points.
- Assessed data and communicated actionable recommendations to business leadership based on data trends.
- Improved reliability of supply chain software, systems, database and order processing through process evaluation to ensure accuracy and correct frequency.
- Reviewed and provided comments on the adequacy of documents and took necessary steps to cure any deficiencies.

#### DB Insurance, Great Neck, NY

March 2013 – August 2016

Accountant

- Performed accounting functions including gathering and analyzing data, creating and finalizing reports, transaction review and reconciliation ensuring accuracy.
- Created and generated monthly 30-60-90 day past due report to track defaulted donors. Evaluated open accounts to review past due balances and pursue collection strategies.
- Responsible for accounts receivable functions, including cash receipts posting, updating cash flow reports and researching chargebacks and write-offs.
- Reviewed and processed chargeback notifications to customers for payment avoiding releasing debt to collection agencies.
- Communicated with customers to verify and update account information. Maintained all financial information confidential.

#### United Hood Cleaning, Woodside, NY

June 2012 – January 2013

Administrative Assistant

- Managed daily office operations and provided comprehensive office-wide administrative support, including organizing files, creating documents and spreadsheets and calendar management.
- Managed receptionist area, including greeting and directing visitors and responding to telephone and in-person requests.
- Managed and dispersed incoming office mail. Organized and processed report and publication mailings.
- Handled complex calendar scheduling for management team. Verified and confirmed meetings and attendees. Prepared meeting
  agendas and complied detailed meeting notes.
- Supervised junior administrative staff. Created administrative and procedural processes to improve accuracy and efficiency.
- Processed company payroll and managed time and attendance systems. Posted open positions on company website

## Pro Design Inc., Astoria, NY

January 2009 - March 2011

Accounts Payable Associate

• Executed accounts payable processes ensuring accuracy and efficiency. Managed payment processing, expense reporting and timely invoice review. Reconciled bank statements and performed entry verification.

#### Dewhurst Macfarlane & Partners, New York, NY

February 2007 – July 2008

Accounts Receivable Clerk

• Processed and recorded all payment transactions, including cash, checks, and vouchers. Produced invoices and communicated with customers regarding payments.

#### **EDUCATION**

Queens College of the City University of New York, Queens NY

Bachelor of Arts, Accounting & Information Systems

2008